<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!-- Copyright 2008 Google Inc. All Rights Reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd" [
<!-- These entities were defined by the orgininal DOQQ header -->
<!ENTITY QUADRANGLE_NAME "SAN FRANCISCO SOUTH">
<!ENTITY QUADRANT "SW">
<!ENTITY WEST_LONGITUDE "-122 30  0.000">
<!ENTITY EAST_LONGITUDE "-122 26 15.000">
<!ENTITY NORTH_LATITUDE "37 41 15.000">
<!ENTITY SOUTH_LATITUDE "37 37 30.000">
<!ENTITY PRODUCTION_DATE "1995  5 16">
<!ENTITY RASTER_ORDER "LEFT_RIGHT/TOP_BOTTOM">
<!ENTITY BAND_ORGANIZATION "SINGLE FILE">
<!ENTITY BAND_CONTENT "BLACK&amp;WHITE">
<!ENTITY BITS_PER_PIXEL "8">
<!ENTITY SAMPLES_AND_LINES "6248  7576">
<!ENTITY HORIZONTAL_DATUM "NAD83">
<!ENTITY HORIZONTAL_COORDINATE_SYSTEM "UTM">
<!ENTITY COORDINATE_ZONE "10">
<!ENTITY HORIZONTAL_UNITS "METERS">
<!ENTITY HORIZONTAL_RESOLUTION "1.00">
<!ENTITY SECONDARY_HORIZONTAL_DATUM "NAD27">
<!ENTITY XY_ORIGIN "543688.000  4171593.000">
<!ENTITY SECONDARY_XY_ORIGIN "543784.673  4171395.980">
<!ENTITY NATION "US">
<!ENTITY STATE "CA">
<!ENTITY NW_QUAD_CORNER_XY "544084.434  4171261.017">
<!ENTITY NE_QUAD_CORNER_XY "549595.031  4171292.255">
<!ENTITY SE_QUAD_CORNER_XY "549636.622  4164358.070">
<!ENTITY SW_QUAD_CORNER_XY "544121.403  4164326.850">
<!ENTITY SECONDARY_NW_QUAD_XY "544085.528  4171056.101">
<!ENTITY SECONDARY_NE_QUAD_XY "549596.261  4171087.340">
<!ENTITY SECONDARY_SE_QUAD_XY "549637.851  4164153.309">
<!ENTITY SECONDARY_SW_QUAD_XY "544122.496  4164122.089">
<!ENTITY RMSE_XY "2.10">
<!--MULTIPLE SOURCES INCLUDED TOGETHER-->
<!ENTITY IMAGE_SOURCE "BLACK AND WHITE FILM">
<!ENTITY SOURCE_IMAGE_ID "PAPP 5365 131">
<!ENTITY SOURCE_IMAGE_DATE "1993  7 10">
<!ENTITY SOURCE_DEM_DATE "1995  5 16">
<!ENTITY AGENCY "WESTERN MAPPING CENTER (WMC)">
<!ENTITY PRODUCER "WMC">
<!ENTITY PRODUCTION_SYSTEM "DV2.5  10/94OV2.3 9/94">
<!ENTITY STANDARD_VERSION "1996 12">
<!ENTITY METADATA_DATE "1997  6  4">
<!ENTITY DATA_FILE_SIZE "47341096">
<!ENTITY BYTE_COUNT "6248">
<!--These entries have been calculated by CaSIL from the DOQ Header-->
<!ENTITY dsn "o37122f4sw_1">
<!ENTITY odb_version_nbr "1">
<!ENTITY byname "san_francisco_south_sw">
<!ENTITY earliest_image_date "19930710">
<!ENTITY latest_image_date "19930710">
<!ENTITY primary_source_date "19930710">
<!ENTITY product_group "27">
<!ENTITY westbc "-122.5">
<!ENTITY eastbc "-122.4375">
<!ENTITY northbc "37.6875">
<!ENTITY southbc "37.625">
<!ENTITY rowcount "7576">
<!ENTITY colcount "6248">
<!ENTITY networkr "">

]>

<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
	<origin>California Spatial Information Library</origin>
	<pubdate>&PRODUCTION_DATE;</pubdate>
	<title>Digital Orthophoto Quadrangle &QUADRANGLE_NAME; &QUADRANT; GeoTiff</title>
	<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
	<pubinfo>
	  <pubplace>Sacramento, CA</pubplace>
	  <publish>State of California</publish>
	</pubinfo>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    
    <descript>
      <abstract>Orthophotos combine the image characteristics of a
    photograph with the geometric qualities of a map. The primary
    digital orthophotoquad (DOQ) is a 1-meter ground resolution,
    quarter-quadrangle (3.75-minutes of latitude by 3.75-minutes of
    longitude) image cast on the Universal Transverse Mercator
    Projection (UTM) on the North American Datum of 1983 (NAD83).The
    geographic extent of the DOQ is equivalent to a quarter-quad plus
    The overedge ranges a minimum of 50 meters to a maximum of 300
    meters beyond the extremes of the primary and secondary corner
    points. The overedge is included to facilitate tonal matching for
    mosaicking and for the placement of the NAD83 and secondary datum
    corner ticks. The normal orientation of data is by lines (rows)
    and samples (columns). Each line contains a series of pixels
    ordered from west to east with the order of the lines from north
    to south.  The radiometric image brightness values are stored as
    256 gray levels ranging from 0 to 255. The metadata provided in
    the digital orthophoto contain a wide range of descriptive
    information including format source information, production
    instrumentation and dates, and data to assist with displaying and
    georeferencing the image. The standard distribution format of DOQs
    will be JPEG compressed images on CD-ROM by counties or special
    regions. The reconstituted image from the CD-ROM will exhibit some
    radiometric differences when compared to its uncompressed original
    but will retain the geometry of the uncompressed DOQ. Uncompressed
    DOQs are distributed on tape. The standard, archived digital
    orthophoto is formatted as four ASCII header records, followed by
    a series of 8-bit binary image data records.</abstract>

    <purpose>DOQ's serve a variety of purposes, from interim maps
    to field references for earth science investigations and
    analysis. The DOQ is useful as a layer of a geographic
    information system and as a tool for revision of digital line
    graphs and topographic maps.</purpose>

    <supplinf>These DOQ's have been made available thru the California
    Spatial Information Library URL:http://gis.ca.gov.  They have been
    reformatted into GeoTIFF format, with a metadata an FGDC compliant
    metadata entry in the description tag.</supplinf>    
  </descript>

  <timeperd>
    <timeinfo>
      <rngdates>
        <begdate>&earliest_image_date;</begdate>
        <enddate>&latest_image_date;</enddate>
      </rngdates>
    </timeinfo>

    <current>ground condition</current>
  </timeperd>

  <status>
    <progress>In work</progress>
    <update>irregular</update>
  </status>

  <spdom>
    <bounding>
      <westbc>&westbc;</westbc>
      <eastbc>&eastbc;</eastbc>
      <northbc>&northbc;</northbc>
      <southbc>&southbc;</southbc>
    </bounding>
  </spdom>

  <keywords>
    <theme>
      <themekt>None</themekt>
      <themekey>DOQ</themekey>
      <themekey>DOQQ</themekey>
      <themekey>digital orthophoto</themekey>
      <themekey>digital orthophotoquad</themekey>
      <themekey>digital image map</themekey>
      <themekey>aerial photograph</themekey>
      <themekey>rectified photograph</themekey>
      <themekey>rectified image</themekey>
      <themekey>orthophoto</themekey>
      <themekey>quarter-quadrangle orthophoto</themekey>
      <themekey>1-meter orthophoto</themekey>
      <themekey>2-meter orhtophoto</themekey>
      <themekey>3.75- x 3.75-minute orthophoto</themekey>
      <themekey>7.5- x 7.5-minute orthophoto</themekey>
    </theme>

    <place>
      <placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1977, Countries,
      dependencies, areas of special sovereignty, and their
      principal administrative divisions (Federal Information
      Processing Standard 10-3):Washington, D.C., National
      Institute of Standards and Technology.</placekt>
      <placekey>&NATION;</placekey>
    </place>

    <place>
      <placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1987, Codes for the
      identification of the States, the District of Columbia and
      the outlying areas of The United States, and associated areas
      (Federal Information Processing Standard 5-2): Washington, D.
      C., National Institute of Standards and Technology.</placekt>
      <placekey>&STATE;</placekey>
    </place>

    <place>
      <placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce,1990, Counties and
      equivalent entities of The United States, its possessions,
      and associated areas (Federal Information Processing Standard
      6-4): Washington, D.C. National Institute of Standards and
      Technology.</placekt>
      <placekey>FIPS code for county or counties.</placekey>
    </place>

      <place>
	<placekt>National Mapping Program, Orthophotomaps</placekt>
	<placekey>&QUADRANGLE_NAME;</placekey>
      </place>
  </keywords>

  <accconst>None</accconst>
  <useconst>None. Acknowledgement of the U.S. Geological Survey
  would be appreciated in products derived from these
  data.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
	<cntorgp>
	  <cntorg>California Spatial Information Library</cntorg>
	</cntorgp>
	<cntaddr>
	  <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
	  <address>900 N. Street</address>
	  <city>Sacramento</city>
	  <state>CA</state>
	  <postal></postal>
	</cntaddr>
	<cntvoice>916 653 9990</cntvoice>
	<cntemail>casil@gis.ca.gov</cntemail>
	
	<cntinst>CaSIL URL:http://gis.ca.gov/ is providing this
	  dataset via an online option not offered by the U. S. Geological
	  Survey.  For information on the original distribution, see the
	  coomplete list of Earth Science Information Centers at:
	  &lt;URL:http://www-nmd.usgs.gov/esic/esic_index.html&gt;
	</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  <datacred>This dataset was created solely by the U.S. Geological
  Survey.  CaSIL only reformatted the dataset for its use.  Please
  acknowledge the U.S. Geological Survey for derived products from
  this dataset.</datacred>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
	<origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
	<pubdate>&PRODUCTION_DATE;</pubdate>
	<title>Digital Orthophoto Quadrangle &QUADRANGLE_NAME; &QUADRANT;</title>
	<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
	<pubinfo>
	  <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
	  <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
	</pubinfo>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>

</idinfo>

<dataqual>
  <attracc>
    <attraccr>During photographic reproduction of the source
    photography, limited analog dodging is performed to improve
    image quality. Analog dodging consists of holding back light
    from certain areas of the sensitized photographic material to
    avoid overexposure. The diapositive is inspected to insure
    clarity and radiometric uniformity. Diapositive image
    brightness values are collected with a minimum of image quality
    manipulation. Image brightness values may deviate from
    brightness values of the original imagery due to image value
    interpolation during the scanning and rectification processes.
    Radiometry is verified by visual inspection of the digital
    orthophoto quadrangle with the original unrectified image to
    determine if the digital orthophoto has the same or better
    image quality as the original unrectified input image. Slight
    systematic radiometric differences can be detected between
    adjacent DOQ files due primarily to differences in source
    photography capture dates and sun angles of aerial photography
    along flight lines. These differences can be observed in an
    image's general lightness or darkness when compared to adjacent
    DOQ file coverages.</attraccr>
  </attracc>

  <logic>All DOQ header data and image file sizes are validated by
  the Tape Validation System (TVS) software prior to archiving in
  the National Digital Cartographic Data Base (NDCDB). This
  validation procedure assures correct physical format and field
  values for header record elements. Logical relationships between
  header record elements are tested.</logic>

  <complete>All DOQ imagery is visually inspected for completeness
  to ensure that no gaps, or image misplacement exist in the 3.75'
  image area or in overedge coverage. DOQ images may be derived by
  mosaicking multiple images, in order to insure complete coverage.
  All DOQ's are cloud free within the 3.75' image area. Some clouds
  may, very infrequently, be encountered only in the overedge
  coverage. Source photography is leaf-off in deciduous vegetation
  regions. Void areas having a radiometric value of zero and
  appearing black may exist. These are areas for which no
  photographic source is available or result from image
  transformation from other planimetric systems to the Universal
  Transverse Mercator (UTM). In the latter case, the void sliver
  areas are on the outside edges of the overedge area. The data set
  field content of each DOQ header record element is validated to
  assure completeness prior to archiving in the NDCDB.</complete>

  <posacc>
    <horizpa>
      <horizpar>The DOQ horizontal positional accuracy and the
      assurance of that accuracy depend, in part, on the accuracy
      of the data inputs to the rectification process. These inputs
      consist of the digital elevation model
      (DEM),aerotriangulation control and methods, the photo source
      camera calibration, scanner calibration, and aerial
      photographs that meet National Aerial Photography Program
      (NAPP) standards. The vertical accuracy of the verified USGS
      format DEM is equivalent to or better than a USGS level 1 or
      2 DEM, with a root mean square error (RMSE) of no greater
      than 7.0 meters. Field control is acquired by third order
      class 1 or better survey methods sufficiently spaced to meet
      National Map Accuracy Staandards (NMAS) for 1:12,000-scale
      products. Aerial cameras have current certification from the
      USGS, National Mapping Division, Optical Science Laboratory.
      Test calibration scans are performed on all source
      photography scanners. Horizontal positional accuracy is
      determined by the Orthophoto Accuracy (ORACC) software
      program for DOQ data produced by the National Mapping
      Division. The program determines the accuracy by finding the
      line and sample coordinates of the passpoints in the DOQ and
      fitting these to their ground coordinates to develop a root
      mean square error (RMSE). From 4 to 9 points are checked. As
      a further accuracy test, the image line and sample
      coordinates of the DEM corners are transformed and compared
      with the actual X,Y DEM corner values to determine if they
      are within the RMSE. Additional information on this testing
      procedure can be found in U.S. Department of the Interior,
      U.S. Geological Survey, 1993, Technical Instructions, ORACC
      Users Manual (draft): Reston, VA. Adjacent DOQ's, when
      displayed together in a common planimetric coordinate system,
      may exhibit slight positional discrepancies across common DOQ
      boundaries. Linear features, such as streets, may not be
      continuous. These edge mismatches, however, still conform to
      positional horizontal accuracy within the NMAS. Field
      investigations to validate DOQ positional accuracy reliabilty
      are periodically conducted by the USGS, National Mapping
      Division, Geometronics Standards Section. DOQ's produced by
      cooperators and contractors use similarly approved RMSE test
      procedures.</horizpar>

      <qhorizpa>
        <horizpav>RMSE</horizpav>
        <horizpae>U.S.Bureau of the Budget, 1947, United States
        National Map Accuracy Standard.</horizpae>
      </qhorizpa>
    </horizpa>
  </posacc>

  <lineage>
    <srcinfo>
      <srccite>
	  <citeinfo>
	    <origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
	    <pubdate>&PRODUCTION_DATE;</pubdate>
	    <title>Digital Orthophoto Quadrangle &QUADRANGLE_NAME; &QUADRANT;</title>
	    <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
	    <pubinfo>
	      <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
	      <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
	    </pubinfo>
	  </citeinfo>
	</srccite>
      <srcscale>12000</srcscale>
      <typesrc>USGS Digital Orthophoto</typesrc>

      <srctime>
        <timeinfo>
          <rngdates>
            <begdate>&earliest_image_date;</begdate>
            <enddate>&latest_image_date;</enddate>
          </rngdates>
        </timeinfo>

        <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
      </srctime>
      <srccitea>DOQ</srccitea>
      <srccontr>The image data that was reformatted.</srccontr>
    </srcinfo>

    <procstep>
	<procdesc>The standard USGS Digital Orthophoto Quadrangle was
	  reformatted into an GeoTiff file.  The software used was GDAL,
	  and libgeotiff, both available at
	  URL:http://www.remotesensing.org/
	</procdesc>
	<srcused>DOQ</srcused>
      <procdate>2002-06</procdate>
    </procstep>
  </lineage>
</dataqual>

<!-- Spatial Domain Information in the GeoTiff tags -->
<!-- Spatial Reference Information in the GeoTiff tags -->

<eainfo>
  <overview>
    <eaover>For DOQ's from panchromatic source each pixel contains
    an 8-bit gray-scale value between 0-255. A value of 0
    represents the color black while a value of 255 represents the
    color white. All values between 0 and 255 are repesented as a
    shade of gray varying from black to white. For color-infrared
    and natural color DOQs' a digital number from 0 to 255 will
    also be asssigned to each pixel but that number will refer to a
    color look-up table which will contain the RGB red, blue and
    green (RGB) values, each from 0 to 255, for that digital
    number. Areas where the rectification process is incomplete due
    to incomplete data (i.e., lack of elevation data, gaps), are
    represented with the numeric value of 0.</eaover>

    <eadetcit>U.S. Department of the Interior, U.S. Geological
    Survey, 1992, Standards for digital orthophotos: Reston, VA. A
    hypertext version is available at: &lt;URL:
    ftp://www-nmd.usgs.gov/pub/doq_html/standards_doq.html&gt;
    Softcopy in ASCII format is available at: &lt;URL:
    ftp://www-nmd.usgs.gov/pub/ti/DOQ/doqstnds/stdoqpt1.txt&gt;
    &lt;URL:
    ftp://www-nmd.usgs.gov/pub/ti/DOQ/doqstnds/stdoqpt2.txt&gt;
    Softcopy in WordPerfect format is available at: &lt;URL:
    ftp://www-nmd.usgs.gov/pub/ti/DOQ/doqstnds/stdoqpt1.wp5&gt;
    &lt;URL:
    ftp://www-nmd.usgs.gov/pub/ti/DOQ/doqstnds/stdoqpt2.wp5&gt;
    Softcopy in PostScript format is available at: &lt;URL:
    ftp://www-nmd.usgs.gov/pub/ti/DOQ/doqstnds/stdoqpt1.ps&gt;
    &lt;URL:
    ftp://www-nmd.usgs.gov/pub/ti/DOQ/doqstnds/stdoqpt2.ps&gt;
    Softcopy in hypertext is available at: &lt;URL:
    ftp://www-nmd.usgs.gov/pub/doq_html/standards_doq.html&gt;</eadetcit>
  </overview>
</eainfo>

<distinfo>
  <distrib>
    <cntinfo>
      <cntorgp>
        <cntorg>California Spatial Information Library</cntorg>
      </cntorgp>
      <cntaddr>
        <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
        <address>900 N. Street</address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>CA</state>
        <postal></postal>
      </cntaddr>
	<cntvoice>916 653 9990</cntvoice>
      <cntemail>casil@gis.ca.gov</cntemail>

      <cntinst>CaSIL URL:http://gis.ca.gov/ is providing this
      dataset via an online option not offered by the U. S. Geological
      Survey.  For information on the original distribution, see the
      coomplete list of Earth Science Information Centers at:
      &lt;URL:http://www-nmd.usgs.gov/esic/esic_index.html&gt;
	</cntinst>
    </cntinfo>
  </distrib>

  <resdesc>Digital Orthophotoquad</resdesc>

  <distliab>Although these data have been processed successfully on a
  computer system at the U.S. Geological Survey, and further at the
  California Spatial Information Library, CaSIL, no warranty expressed
  or implied is made by the USGS or CaSIL regarding the utility of the
  data on any other system, nor shall the act of distribution
  constitute any such warranty.</distliab>

  <stdorder>
    <digform>
      <digtinfo>
	  <formname>image/geotiff</formname> <formcont>USGS DOQ image
	  file stored as an extension to the TIFF file format to allow
	  for geographic coordinate systems to be identified with the
	  dataset.  See URL:http://www.geotiff.org/ for more
	  details.</formcont>
      </digtinfo>
	<digtopt>
	  <onlinopt>
	    <computer>
	      <networka>
		<networkr>&networkr;</networkr>
	      </networka>
	    </computer>
	  </onlinopt>
	</digtopt>
    </digform>
    <fees>The online copy of the data set (when available
	electronically) may be accessed without charge.</fees>
  </stdorder>
</distinfo>

<metainfo>
  <metd>2002-06-01</metd>
  <metc>
    <cntinfo>
      <cntorgp>
        <cntorg>California Spatial Information Library</cntorg>
      </cntorgp>
      <cntaddr>
        <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
        <address>900 N. Street</address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>CA</state>
        <postal></postal>
      </cntaddr>
	<cntvoice>916 653 9990</cntvoice>
      <cntemail>casil@gis.ca.gov</cntemail>
    </cntinfo>
  </metc>

  <metstdn>Content Standards for Digital Geospatial
  Metadata</metstdn>

  <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
</metainfo>

</metadata>
